http://www.carnegielearning.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Effective: August 1, 2019
This website is developed and maintained by Carnegie Learning, Inc. (hereinafter “Carnegie Learning,” “we” or “us”).  This Privacy Policy communicates our Privacy practices to parents, teachers, and schools and school district administrators, collectively “you,” who license our products and services for either your own use or the use of your students.  Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By continuing to interact with our digital properties, you agree to the practices described in this Privacy Policy on behalf of yourself and your students.
When you visit our website, or use our software or mobile applications (“apps,”) collectively our “digital properties,” Carnegie Learning may collect and use certain information about you and your students.  Carnegie Learning recognizes that you care about how your information, and the information of your students, is used.  This Privacy Policy explains how we may collect and use your and your student’s information, particularly personal information, and the choices you can make about what information about you and your students is shared.
This Privacy Policy applies to carnegielearning.com, longlivemath.com, emcl.com, emcschool.com and associated domains and subdomains, our software and apps, and covers information collected in connection with access and use of our digital properties. This Privacy Policy applies whether access or use of the digital properties is via personal computer, mobile device, or otherwise and to interactive features or downloads that are owned and operated by Carnegie Learning and its subsidiaries and that are available through the digital properties.
PLEASE NOTE: While most Carnegie Learning websites are general audience websites through which we do not knowingly collect information from children under 13 (“Children” and each, a “Child”), portions of the websites, certain subdomains, our software, and our apps are directed to children under 13. These subdomains, software, and apps contain teaching and learning resources designed for students in pre-K through college.  Students may access those digital properties directed to children only after their teacher or school or school district administrator has entered into a license with Carnegie Learning and has provided the students with access. The subdomains, software, and apps that are directed to children will follow our Children’s Privacy Policy.  In addition, our use of student information is described in Section 7. How Does Carnegie Learning Handle Student Information.
1.  Changes to this Privacy Policy
We ask that you periodically review our Privacy Policy to be sure you are familiar with the most current version. The Policy will state its effective date, which is the most recent date on which we revised the Policy. Carnegie Learning reserves the right to make immaterial changes to our Privacy Policy that will not affect Carnegie Learning’s use of a user’s personally identifiable information at any time without any notice to you other than posting any such changes in a revised Privacy Policy on the our digital properties. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy that increase our rights to use personal information we have previously collected about you, we will obtain your consent for those changes, as they relate both to your information, and to your students’ information, either through an email to your registered email address, or by prominent posting on our digital properties. If such changes occur, you will be asked to consent to these changes before continuing use of relevant digital properties.
2. Information Collected by Carnegie Learning, Inc.
Carnegie Learning collects information about you when you interact with our digital properties.  Our digital properties are directed toward two audiences:
Teachers or administrators of a school or school district (collectively, “Non-Student Users”); and
Students.
Our privacy practices, including the type of data we collect, vary by digital property and audience. For detailed information on how we handle student information, please see Section 7. How Does Carnegie Learning Handle Student Information.
We may automatically collect information about the devices you use to interact with our digital properties and how you interact with our digital properties. The information we automatically collect may include your IP addresses, device identifiers, web browser types and versions, approximate locations based on IP addresses, search terms and results within the Site, date, time, and pages viewed, and your languages.
In order to provide you services and contact you about our products and services, we may request your email address and other personal information. If you wish to unsubscribe from promotional communications, you can use https://discover.carnegielearning.com/Subscription-Center.html.
Carnegie Learning digital properties do not collect personal information about your online activities across third-party websites or online services.  Therefore, “do not track” signals transmitted from web browsers do not apply to our digital properties, and we do not alter any of our data collection and use practices upon receipt of such a signal.
Carnegielearning.com provides information about our products, services, and resources for teachers or school or school district administrators. In addition, certain subdomains of carnegielearning.com provide direct access to these products, services, and resources for Non-Student Users who have licensed these products. In order to use many of these features, tools and services, we ask you to register to become a member. During this member registration process, and through other interactions on our digital properties, we collect information teachers and administrators provide to us including, but not limited to, your name, the school or school district you work for, the physical address of your school, your job title, the grades and curricula you teach, your email address, and your phone number. We may also ask Non-Student Users for information about usage of various products and services as well as satisfaction with those products and services.
3. How Does Carnegie Learning Use The Information Collected About Non-Student Users?
Carnegie Learning may use the information it collects about non-student users for a number of purposes, including:
To manage Carnegie Learning’s everyday business needs, such as administration and improvement of our digital properties;
To communicate with teachers, and schools and school district administrators, and support customer communications;
To offer you information and promotional material about the products and services you see on our digital properties;
To analyze the performance and functioning of the digital properties, including to test, correct and improve our content, applications and services;
To develop new applications, products and services;
To research how users interact with the digital properties and to perform other market research;
For investigation of information security and information asset protection-related incidents; and
To prevent fraud or other potentially illegal activities, to enforce our Terms of Use, to comply with all applicable laws and Carnegie Learning’s corporate reporting obligations, and to enforce Carnegie Learning’s agreements.
To analyze academic and learning outcomes and preferences
For external academic research and scholarship
Carnegie Learning does not retain usage information from users of any demonstration or trial versions of its products after the conclusion of the trial period. If users provide contact information, we may use that contact information to communicate with them to provide additional information and promotional materials.
For detailed information on how we handle student information, please see Section 7. How Does Carnegie Learning Handle Student Information.
4.  When does Carnegie Learning Share Non-Student Information?
Carnegie Learning may share your information with third parties who perform services and functions on our behalf to support our interactions with you including, for example, by fulfilling information requests, administering surveys or contests, providing necessary technical services, or communicating with you. However, all such third parties have no independent rights to your information and are prohibited from using your information in any way that contradicts Carnegie Learning's privacy policy.
Carnegie Learning may share your information with third parties, including law enforcement authorities, to:
Enforce its Terms of Use;
Protect Carnegie Learning’s property, services and legal rights;
Prevent physical harm to the persons or property of others;
Prevent fraud or potentially illegal activities against Carnegie Learning and others;
Support auditing, compliance, and corporate governance functions;
Test, correct, and improve our content, applications, and services;
Develop new applications, products, and services;
Analyze academic and learning outcomes and preferences;
For external academic research and scholarship;
Comply with subpoenas, court orders, or similar legal processes, including from law enforcement agencies, regulators and courts; and
Comply with any and all applicable laws.
Carnegie Learning also may share any personally identifiable or other information about you that Carnegie Learning obtains with any or all of its subsidiaries and affiliates in order to accomplish these purposes.
Carnegie Learning also may provide to third parties, including other businesses and members of the public, aggregated statistical data showing general usage patterns and statistics about our digital properties, interactions, and transactions. This data does not personally identify you or provide specific information about individual usage.
5.  What If You Don’t Want Carnegie Learning to Automatically Collect Your Information?
Carnegie Learning may begin collecting information as soon as you or your students visit our digital properties.  By using our digital properties, you permit Carnegie Learning to collect and use your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. By directing your students to our digital properties, you consent to our collection and use of their information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and, in particular, with Section 7. How Does Carnegie Learning Handle Student Information and Section 11. Children’s Privacy Policy.
Many Internet browsers and mobile devices allow you to block the transmission of information, such as your IP address or geolocation information, or to block the installation of cookies. You may choose to enable these options. However, enabling these options may prevent you from using many of the core features and functions available on our digital properties.
You can review, modify, and delete certain information related to your use of our digital properties by accessing your Carnegie Learning account.  You can unsubscribe to email, text, or other messages in your account settings or by following the instructions contained within the message. You can also ask us to update your information by contacting us at privacy@carnegielearning.com.
6. How does Carnegie Learning Use Cookies?
When you use our digital properties, Carnegie Learning may store data in “cookies,” or similar technology on your devices.  Carnegie Learning may use stored data to collect information about how you use our digital properties, to deliver content specific to your interests, and to track the pages you’ve visited. These data allow us to use the information we collect to customize your Carnegie Learning experience so that your visit to Carnegie Learning is as relevant and as valuable to you as possible.  Certain browsers may allow you to disable cookies.  However, disabling cookies from Carnegie Learning may prevent you from using various features of our digital properties.
7. How Does Carnegie Learning Handle Student Information?
Carnegie Learning is committed to protecting information about all of its customers. As part of this commitment, we work with educational institutions that must comply with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and state laws to help ensure student education record data is handled in a manner consistent with the applicable educational institution’s privacy policy.
Carnegie Learning collects and maintains information on students for the benefit of teachers, schools and school district administrators who license our products and services. We collect student information through our digital properties that provide teaching and learning resources designed for students in pre-K through college including, but not limited to, MyCL, MATHia, MATHiaU, Zulama, Passport, MyPL, Bookshelf and digital applications and materials available through these products and our websites.
K-12 students cannot independently access our teaching and learning resources. The teachers, parents, schools and school district administrators who license our products and services provide students with access to an account. Information collected about students may include:
First and Last Name (optional);
Email address (optional);
Student identifier (optional);
Student login ID and password (unique to our system)
Student profile picture (optional)
The class and school where a student is enrolled;
Student-generated content, including text, videos and other responses to questions, prompts and assignments
Feedback about any of our products and services
Data generated from student activity within the digital properties, including answers provided, errors, hint requests, preferences, timing information, progress within the system, and inferences made from the this data about student knowledge.
External assessment scores used to customize instruction
In addition, we may automatically collect information about the devices students use to interact with our digital properties. The information we automatically collect may include IP address, device identifier, web browser type and version, pages and activities viewed, and the date and time of use. Any usage information, device identifier, or other persistent identifier we collect is used for the sole purpose of providing support for the digital properties’ internal operations.
Schools, school districts, parents, and students may ask to review the information that Carnegie Learning has collected and retained about a particular student, as well as request its deletion by contacting us at privacy@carnegielearning.com.
Carnegie Learning may use the information collected about students to:
Help students reset their passwords;
Investigate information security and information asset protection-related incidents;
Test, correct and improve our content, applications and services;
Develop new applications, products and services;
Analyze academic and learning outcomes and preferences;
Personalize the teaching and learning resources available across the digital properties to improve student instruction and meet individual student needs;
Provide reports to teachers or school or school district administrators at the student, class, school, or district level;
Support teachers or school or school district administrators implementing our products or using our services;
Monitor the use of our products and perform such analyses as might be necessary or helpful in improving product performance, efficiency, and security;
Research how students use the digital properties and analyze the educational effectiveness of our products and services to contribute to general knowledge about how students learn;
Provide reports to students, parents or guardians;
For external academic research and scholarship;
Enforce our Terms of Use; and
Use the information as may be required or permitted by legal, regulatory, industry self-regulatory, insurance, audit or security requirements.
In order to provide and support our products, Carnegie Learning may contract with third parties and share information required to carry out these services with these third parties. In such cases, all third parties are required to abide by this policy.
In some cases, the teachers, and schools and school district administrators who license our products and services enter into additional reporting or research agreements for the provision of reports or analyses that require data to be associated with demographic categories (gender, ethnicity, free or reduced lunch status, etc.) or other individual student information, such as test scores. In such cases, the teachers, schools and/or school district administrators provide Carnegie Learning and specified partners with the information required, which may personally identify students. When such agreements are in place, reports containing student information are provided only to the teachers, schools and school district administrators authorized to receive that information. In such cases, data is held securely and only Carnegie Learning employees and partners directly involved in producing these reports have access to students’ personally identifiable information.
Carnegie Learning does not collect or maintain any demographic, academic or other school record information about students, teachers or administrators unless it has a separate reporting or research agreement.
We may have different contractual terms and privacy policies in place with some of our customers. Those other terms and policies may amend this Policy for information collected or released under those terms, but they will never contradict the policy terms described here. If you have any questions as to what legal agreement or privacy policy controls the collection and use of your information, please contact your school district or Carnegie Learning at privacy@carnegielearning.com.
8.  Use of Data for Research
Carnegie Learning uses de-identified and aggregate data about students’ use of our digital properties for product development, research or other purposes. To de-identify data, we remove all direct and indirect personal identifiers. These identifiers include, but are not limited to, name, ID number, teacher name, class and school identifications. Carnegie Learning agrees not to attempt to re-identify any de-identified data. We may store de-identified data indefinitely.
Schools, school districts and individuals may ask for their data to be excluded from any de-identified data sets. To request such exclusion, please email privacy@carnegielearning.com.
In addition, for research and other purposes, Carnegie Learning may transfer de-identified data to third parties.  For example, we may share information such as problems attempted, answers or hint requests for each step of the problem, and associated time stamps. We review all requests for such de-identified data sets, and we require all recipients of de-identified data sets to agree to the Carnegie Learning Private Dataset Terms of Use, which prohibit, among other things, any attempts to re-identify the de-identified data and any commercial use of the data.
In connection with research studies, Carnegie Learning and/or its partners may publish or discuss aggregate data about student performance and results. Such publications never reference individual information, only aggregate statistics. Research projects that make use of student data are reviewed by an Institutional Review Board (IRB) which is responsible for approving the goals and procedures of the study, including those related to maintaining privacy of information. The IRB may or may not require parental or student notification or approval. Schools or school districts provide prior consent to any research that involves interaction with the schools and their students’ information. Carnegie Learning is committed to abiding by IRB recommendations and requirements.
As part of our commitment to continual improvement, Carnegie Learning may field test new application content and features within our products. We may also partner with third-party researchers to conduct such research. If the research is not exempt from IRB review, an Institutional Review Board (IRB) will review the goals and procedures of the study, including those related to maintaining privacy of information.
9. How Does Carnegie Learning Protect My Information?
Carnegie Learning has implemented an information security program with numerous measures, including administrative, technical and physical controls that are designed to reasonably safeguard information that can individually identify you against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We recommend that you do not share your password with anyone.
Data Retention, Access, and Security
At the end of each school year or upon termination of the district contract, Carnegie Learning will notify school districts that all personally-identifiable student data in its possession or in the possession of any subcontractors or agents to which we may have transferred the information will be either destroyed or de-identified. Districts may request a copy of the data or that we retain the data on their behalf by emailing their request to privacy@carnegielearning.com within 60 days of such notification.
10. California Privacy Rights
Carnegie Learning does not share any personal information with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If this practice changes, we will notify you by prominent posting on our digital properties.
The portions of the digital properties directed to students and children under 13 do not enable or have a forum for the posting or sharing of content or information.
11. Children’s Privacy Policy
While most of carnegielearning.com is a general audience website that does not knowingly collect information from children under 13 (“Children” and each, a “Child”), portions of the digital properties, are directed to children under 13, and we may collect information directly from children under 13 in connection with those portions of the digital properties. Therefore, Carnegie Learning provides this Children’s Privacy Policy to explain our privacy practices with respect to children under 13 who access and use our digital properties.
Carnegie Learning collects personal information about children under 13 for the use and benefit of teachers or school or school district administrators, and for no other commercial purpose. We limit the use of information about children under 13 to the educational context authorized by the school.
Through this Privacy Policy, we provide each school with all the notices required under COPPA, contained within this Privacy Policy. Parents also can request a copy of these notices and request access to their child’s personal information to review and/or have the information deleted by contacting privacy@carnegielearning.com.
Collection & Use of Information from Children Under 13
The information we directly collect on children under 13 includes:
First and Last Name (optional);
Email address (optional);
Student identifier (optional);
Student login ID and password (unique to our system)
Student profile picture (optional)
The class and school where a student is enrolled;
Student-generated content, including text, videos and other responses to questions, prompts and assignments
Data generated from student activity within the digital properties, including answers provided, errors, hint requests, preferences, timing information, progress within the system, and inferences made from the this data about student knowledge.
Feedback about any of our products and services
External assessment scores used to customize instruction
We do not enable children under 13 to make their personal information publicly available.
Carnegie Learning uses the information collected on children under 13 to:
Help students reset their passwords;
Personalize the teaching and learning resources available on our digital properties to improve student instruction and meet individual student needs;
Provide reports to teachers or school or school district administrators at the student, class, school, or district level;
Support teachers or school or school district administrators implementing our products or using our services;
Monitor the use of our products and perform such analyses as might be necessary or helpful in improving product performance, efficiency, and security;
Research how students use the digital properties and perform analysis directed at improving the educational effectiveness of our products and services and to contribute to general knowledge about how students learn; and
Provide reports to students, parents or guardians.
Carnegie Learning will not use any information collected about children under 13 to advertise or market to students or their parents.
In addition, we may automatically collect information about the devices children under 13 use to interact with our digital properties. The information we automatically collect may include IP address, device identifier, web browser type and version, pages and activities viewed, and the date and time of use. Any usage information, device identifier, or other persistent identifier we collect is used for the sole purpose of providing support for the digital properties’ internal operations.
Disclosure of Information from Children Under 13
Carnegie Learning may rely on third party service providers who provide support for the internal operations of the digital properties, such as hosting the website, designing and/or operating our digital properties’ features, tracking analytics, or performing other administrative services. These third party service providers are held to the same obligations as Carnegie Learning with regard to information from children under 13, do not disclose or use information for any other purpose, and are subject to the terms of this agreement.
12. Transfer of Assets
In the event of any acquisition, reorganization or merger of Carnegie Learning or its assets, your information may be transferred as part of the transaction to an assignee. The assignee will assume and be subject to the same obligations of the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy as Carnegie Learning. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Carnegie Learning may continue to use the information you provide to us as set forth in this Privacy Policy and in our Terms of Use. In the unlikely event that the likelihood of us going out of business or entering bankruptcy is imminent, we will provide you with thirty (30) days’ notice to use the Service and after such 30 days all data will be transferred to the assignee.
13.  Contact Us
For any questions about Carnegie Learning, our privacy policies, or to request review and/or removal of information collected by Carnegie Learning, please call us toll free at 1-877-401-2527 or contact us at:
Carnegie Learning
501 Grant Street
Union Trust Building, Suite 1075
Pittsburgh, PA 15219
privacy@carnegielearning.com
For questions about ongoing or potential research projects, please email research@carnegielearning.com.
To report technical issues with the Site or apps, or to submit feature requests, please Contact Us using the appropriate form.
File Downloads Available Form Include child page summaries.
Close
Home
Products
Our Products
CL OverviewEMC SchoolContinuous Learning Resources and SupportBlended Solutions
Middle School Math SolutionHigh School Math SolutionSoftware Platforms
MATHia® (Grades 6-12)MATHiaU™ (Higher Ed)Zulama™ (Computer Science)
